I've heard that at some schools, if
you'd like try and do really well, you
almost get picked on for like being a
nerd or something.
>> I think when I was 10, I started to get
called a boffin.
>> Yeah, I think at a young age, I was
quite conflicted because my family was
all about grades and they really wanted
me to do well at school. And then my
friends, or basically everyone in the
classroom at school, seemed to think it
was awful that I got good grades and
would call me a boffin. And it was very
much like it made me feel very othered,
you know, in a sort of kind of like a
bullying sort of way.
>> That's exactly what you don't want your
kids to go through because first of all,
you don't nobody wants their kids to be
bullied. Second of all, the last thing
you want them to be bullied for is
trying to do well at school. So, this is
difficult. We should also explain to the
listeners what Okay, so what is a
boffin?
>> What is a boffin? A boffin is usually a
word for like a clever clog, a really
brainy person, right? But I guess it's
used in a negative sense in in that way.
But you can talk about a boffin meaning
a sort of someone who's a nerd or maybe
a scientist or something.
>> Exactly. You'd be like, "Oh, the boffins
at NASA have done a space thing or
whatever." But you were getting picked
on at school for trying to do well.
>> Yeah. Or sometimes it's not even like I
was trying to do well, I would just do
well and then suddenly be sort of made
fun of. So, I was like, "Oh, should I
not do well?" But I didn't I didn't
really try to not do well, but I could
see how you would. I could see how you'd
be like, "Oh, I should just like start
failing at school. Then I'll be cooler."
>> Yeah.
>> [music]